# HITESH BHATIA

New Delhi, India

+91 9871983559

https://www.linkedin.com/in/hiteshbhatia3559

hiteshbhatia3559@gmail.com

# **SUMMARY**

Currently looking for Cyber Security roles with a focus on scripting, engineering, innovation and clientside engagements. Possessing experience in leading and managing student teams, with 50+ awards in debates, in addition to clientside engagements. Six years of practical hands on experience in Photoshop. Completed several small projects in Python. Open to relocate to Tier 1 cities.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**DESIGNATED PARTNER** 

Nov' 2018 - Present

POINT FIVE CAPITAL NEW DELHI

Handling existing and onboarding new clients, raising INR 5M of

Developing manual profitable futures and options strategies Automating existing strategies, deployed to the Crypto market

CYBER SECURITY ANALYST

**ERNST & YOUNG LLP** AEROCITY

June 2018 - Oct' 2018

Designed, wrote and deployed a Python based script called

Deployed to NIC-SOC, the center point of all government internet

traffic in New Delhi Designed and wrote a Thought Leadership around the Crypto space

CYBER SECURITY INTERN

June 2017 - July 2017

MICROSOFT GURGAON, HARYANA

Contributed to the Imagine Academy in Cyber Security initiative Delivered CyberSec awareness sessions with 12 school Principals

and 500+ school students

CYBER SECURITY INTERN

Oct' 2016 - Jan' 2017

MAIN BRAIN TECH HYDERABAD, TELANGANA

Directly handled Android application black box penetration testing Created secure coding guidelines tailor made to the company

CYBER SECURITY INTERN

June 2016 - July 2016

**ERNST & YOUNG LLP** AEROCITY

Advanced SOCs, Deep Web and TOR netowork

### **EDUCATION**

B. TECH - IT - 71%

Aug' 2014 - Aug' 2018

NORTHERN INDIA ENGINEERING COLLEGE

GGSIP University, New Delhi

CLASS 12TH BOARDS - 84%

March 2013 - March 2014

BAL BHARATI PUBLIC SCHOOL, NEW DELHI

# **EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

SECRETARY GENERAL

Oct' 2017

**AWARDS** 

2013 - 2018

**LEADERSHIP** 2015 - 2018

Managed a team of 40 students, and organized Quintessence **Model UN** the largest free of cost Model UN conference held in India at Talkatora Indoor Stadium, in addition to eight other debates organized under Quintessence, the debating society of NIEC.

Over 50 awards and certificates in various capacities - adjudication, excellence in debate, organisation and participation with accolades for verbal communication, technical writing, teamwork and overall

diplomacy

Co - Founded and lead Quintessence as its Vice President and President across three years, organizing multiple trainings targeted at engineering and school students

## TRAININGS CONDUCTED

MAIN SPEAKER

2015 - 2017

Provided the following trainings as the main (and only) speaker: 1. Cyber Security Training - July 2016 - 40 hours, in addition to Website Development and Adobe Photoshop seminars in IEEE NIEC. 2. Five debate and Model UN trainings to a total of 400+ students in government and private schools and colleges across Delhi 3. Darknet and Cryptocurrency Seminar - null community, Bharti Airtel office

## **PROJECTS**

PERSONAL WEBSITE IN PROGRESS

Django based website for professional use https://github.com/hiteshbhatia3559/DjangoProject

TRADING BOT COMPLETED - PROPREITARY

A trend following automated trading bot

TRADING SIGNALS COMPLETED

A comprehensive, three module indicator designed for manual retail trading, overing between 58% to 91% profitability per month depending on volatility.

Developed as a Project in my Final Year, offered as a

lifetime subscription based servi-

-Per unit cost - Approximately 60 USD

-Number of sales - 250+ -Net profit - USD 15,000+

https://www.tradingview.com/script/MvqP3z3k-OneX-HiteshB-Scalping-Indicator-1-0/

AUTO-SQLMAP COMPLETED - PROPREITARY

A proprietary penetration testing tool developed in the NIC-SOC for EY that automaically attempts SQL injection attacks based on vulnerability detection in an iterative, undetectable fashion

**DISCORD BOT COMPLETED** 

A python based Discord bot that shows the price of Bitcoin and Ethereum on Bitmex, along with candlestick charts. Also stores strings that can be called to chat later.

### TECHNOLOGIES USED

**PYTHON** external libraries

django, ccxt, matplotlib, ta-lib, pandas, numpy, backtrader, stem, sqlmap, discordpym mpl-finance

PINESCRIPT tradingview code

Time series analysis, signals, alerts and indicators

VAPT IN KALI LINUX tools used

sqlmap, aircrack-ng, john the ripper, wireshark

**WEB TECHNOLOGIES** 

Intermediate level HTML, CSS3, Js and MVC based frameworks

OTHER INTERESTS

Read over 1000 books to date across genres, with a Budding Writer ward in High School at the BBPSGR farewell

Competitive gamer and occasional streamer on Twitch

Enthusiast of TV shows on and around crime, futurism, the cosmos and alternative history

Part time work as a Graphic Designer, having worked freelance for a multitude of vector and poster requirements

Passive and Active investing in the Cryptocurrency and Equities space, with extensive knowledge and know how of financial markets and products - experience in trading futures and options, perpetual swaps, binary options and traditional forex pairs